Cameron Warburton

Cameron.cw@outlook.com | E-Portfolio | 07539022907

Personal Profile

I have always worked in the IT Support sector but have decided to get into Frontend Development/Web Development as I believe it allows my more creative side to come through and I really enjoying learning new things every day. I have come a long way from when I first starting learning to code in September 2023, and I enjoy working on projects in my spare time as I believe this allows me to learn more and expand my knowledge further. Being in the IT Support sector, I have always enjoyed problem solving and helping others as well which I believe are transferable skills into the world of coding. In my free time I play sports and go to the gym regularly to keep fit and to keep disciplined.

Experience

Frontend Developer Internship |

Jan 2024 - Current

Frontend Simplified

- Transformed a completely static HTML, CSS, JavaScript and React single page application into an interactive user interface using animations, transitions and carousels
- Processed API requests with Axios to dynamically represent data from a cloud server and represented it through skeleton loading states, pagination and dynamic routing
- Utilized Git version control and the GitHub interface to work and thrive in a virtual and collaborative team environment.

Frontend Developer Support

Sep 2023 - Current

Frontend Simplified

- Supported 1,000+ students using HTML, CSS, Flexbox, JavaScript and React best practises
- Utilized debugging best practises using Google Chrome inspect element tooling
- Simplified difficult programming concepts including responsive website development, CSS layout, Promises and API requests

Modern Networks May 2024 – Current

Onsite Engineer

Since moving to Manchester, I have started working for Modern Networks as an Onsite Engineer in the Trafford Centre. I am responsible for monitoring all the switches, UPS's, AP's and CCTV cameras across the two large sites within the Trafford Centre. I am also first point of call for all day-to-day IT issues that may arise amongst other tasks. I am involved in a lot of the projects that are ongoing and involved in the planning for any future projects. In this role I have gained a lot of experience in problem solving and quick thinking, as often I am solving urgent issues.

Rooms and Views Jan 2024 – May 2024

IT Support Engineer

- Setting up accounts and equipment for new starters, including imaging and configuring machines.
- Day to Day IT related issues in the ticketing system
- Networking/Cabling
- Intune Mobile Devices/iPad's
- Desk Setups

Coral Homes (Australia)

April 2023 - Dec 2023

IT Support Officer

- Setting up accounts and equipment for new starters, including imaging and configuring machines.
- Day to Day IT related issues in the ticketing system
- Networking/Cabling
- Phone system management
- Intune Mobile Devices/iPad's
- Desk Setups

Redrow Homes Oct 2017 – Feb 2023

Junior IT Helpdesk Assistant / Junior IT Technician

- Supporting Redrow Development Applications
- Setting up accounts and equipment for new starters, including imaging and configuring machines.
- Day to Day IT related issues in the ticketing system
- Networking/Cabling
- Phone system management
- UPS Maintenance & Swap Outs
- Firewall maintenance
- Sophos Anti-Virus/Email Appliance
- Supporting 2000's staff including IT Development Team.
- MDM Implementation and Setup

Projects

Netflix Clone | Website | GitHub

Created a fully responsive movie app with XYZ functionality (e.g. Google Sign-In, Filter System, Pagination)

Twitter Clone | Still in Development | GitHub

Developed a social media app with XYZ functionality (e.g. Posting Tweets, Commenting, Sharing, Messaging)

Library – E-Commerce Site | Website | GitHub

Created a fully responsive bookstore app with a shopping cart and filtering option for rating, price etc.

Education

BTEC Level 3 Advanced Diploma in Information Technology

Sep 2014 - July 2016

Grade - MMP

Frontend Developer Bootcamp

Sep 2023 - Mar 2024

Frontend Simplified

Technical Skills

Languages: HTML5 | CSS3 (+ SCSS, BEM) | JavaScript ES6+ | Typescript

Frameworks: React (+ hooks) | Next.js | Material-UI | Redux

Technology: NPM | Git | Yarn | React dev tools | Firebase v9 | GitHub